In this video, we're going to talk about the first of three garbage collection
在此视频中，我们将讨论三个垃圾收集中的第一个
techniques that we're going to look at in detail. First one is mark-and-sweep.
我们将详细介绍的技术。第一个是标记和清扫。
Mark-and-sweep works in two phases. And it's called, not surprisingly, mark and
标记和清除分两个阶段工作。它被称为马克和马克，这并不令人惊讶。
sweep. So, the mark phase is going to trace all the reachable objects. So, when
清扫一下。因此，标记阶段将跟踪所有可达对象。那么，什么时候
memory runs out and we stop to do the garbage collection, the first thing we're
内存耗尽，我们停下来进行垃圾收集，我们要做的第一件事
going to do is go and trace out all the reachable objects. And then the Sweep
接下来要做的就是找出所有可到达的对象。然后清扫
phase is going to collect all the garbage objects. And to support this, every object
阶段将收集所有垃圾对象。为了支持这一点，每个物体
is going to have an extra bit somewhere in it called the mark bit. And, this is
在它的某个地方会有一个额外的比特，叫做标记比特。还有，这是
reserved from memory management and it's not going to be used by anything except
从内存管理中保留，并且它不会被任何人使用，除非
the garbage collector. And initially, before we start a garbage collection, the
垃圾收集器。最初，在我们开始垃圾收集之前，
mark bit of every object will always be zero. And that's going to be set to one,
每个对象的标记位将始终为零。这将被设置为1，
for the reachable objects in the mark phase. So, when we mark an object, we mark
用于标记阶段的可访问对象。所以，当我们标记一个物体时，我们就标记了
it with a And that indicates that the object is reachable. So, here is the mark
它带有和，表示该对象是可访问的。所以，这是标记
phase. It's going to be a work list based algorithm and so initially our work list
阶段。这将是一个基于工作列表的算法，所以最初我们的工作列表
consists of all the roots so all the initial pointers held in registers and
由所有根组成，因此寄存器中保存的所有初始指针
then while the work list, the to-do list is not empty, we're going to do the
然后，虽然工作列表、待办事项列表不是空的，但我们要做的是
following. We pick some element v out of the to-do list we'll remove it from the
下面是。我们从待办事项列表中选择一些元素v，然后将其从
to-do list, okay. And then, this is the crux of the algorithm. If the object v is
待办事项清单，好的。然后，这就是算法的症结所在。如果对象v是
not already marked then we mark it, okay. So, we say, mark bit to one and then we
还没有做标记，那我们就做标记，好的。所以，我们说，将比特标记为1，然后我们
find all the pointers inside of it, alright. And we add those to our work
找到里面的所有指针，好的。我们把这些加到我们的工作中
list. So, everything, every point gets added to work list. Now, if v is already
列表。所以，每一件事，每一点都会被添加到工作清单中。现在，如果v已经是
marked, well then we have already processed it and we've already add all the
标记，那么我们已经对其进行了处理，并且我们已经添加了所有
things it points to, to the work list. And so we just need to do nothing there is no
它指向的东西，工作清单。所以我们只需要什么都不做就没有
else branch and we just drop it from the to-do list. So, once we've completed the
Else分支，我们将其从待办事项列表中删除。所以，一旦我们完成了
mark phase and every reachable object has been marked, then the sweep phase is going
标记阶段，并且每个可到达的对象都已被标记，则扫描阶段正在进行
to scan th rough the heap looking for objects that have mark bit zero. And the
扫描整个堆，查找标记位为零的对象。以及
sweep phase is just going to march through all of memory. It's going to start at the
扫描阶段将在所有内存中行进。它将从
bottom of the heap and walk over every object in the heap and check its mark bit.
堆的底部，遍历堆中的每个对象并检查其标记位。
And so, any of the objects that it finds that have mark bit zero, they were not
因此，它发现的任何具有零标记位的对象，它们都不是
visited in mark phase and they're clearly not reachable. S, all those objects will
在标记阶段访问过，显然无法联系到。%s，则所有这些对象都将
be added to a free list. And as we go through the memory is one other detail
被添加到免费列表中。当我们回顾记忆的时候，还有一个细节
that's important. Any object that has its mark bit set is gonna have its mark bit
这很重要。任何设置了其标记位的对象都将具有其标记位
reset to zero. So, that way it's ready for the next garbage collection. So, here is
重置为零。这样，它就为下一次垃圾收集做好了准备。所以，这就是
the pseudo-code for the sweep phase and this will function, size of p is going to
扫描相位的伪代码，这将起作用，p的大小将为
size of block, the size of the object that starts at pointer p, alright. And as
挡路的大小，从指针p开始的对象的大小。以及AS
you'll see this is actually, the reason that we have the size of objects encoded
您将看到这实际上是我们对对象大小进行编码的原因
in the object in COOL. So, remember in the header for COOL objects there is a size
在冷状态下的物体中。所以，请记住，在酷对象的标题中有一个大小
field that is, so that the garbage collector as it's walking through memory
字段，以便垃圾回收器在遍历内存时
can figure out how big the objects are. Anyway, we start at the bottom of the
可以计算出这些物体有多大。不管怎样，我们从最底层开始
heap. And while we haven't reached the top of the heap, we do the following. We look
堆。虽然我们还没有到达堆的顶部，但我们执行以下操作。我们看着
at where we're pointing and then we'll always be pointing to the beginning of an
在我们所指向的地方，然后我们将始终指向一个
object. So, we check to see if the mark bit of that object is one. And if it is,
对象。因此，我们检查该对象的标记位是否为1。如果是的话，
well then it was a reachable object. So, we just reset its mark bit to zero.
好吧，那么它是一个可以触及的物体。因此，我们只需将其标记位重置为零。
Otherwise, if its mark bit was zero, then we're going to add that block of memory,
否则，如果它的标记位是0，那么我们将添加那个挡路内存，
okay, which is the size of the object to the free list. And finally, in either
好的，这是空闲列表中对象的大小。最后，无论是在哪一种情况下
case, okay, we're going to increment p by the size of the object that it points to
在这种情况下，好的，我们将根据它所指向的对象的大小来递增p
so we point to the next object. Then we'll just repeat that loop over and over again
所以我们指向下一个物体。然后我们就一遍又一遍地重复这个循环
resetting the mark bits of things that were reached and adding things that were
重置已到达的内容的标记位，并添加
not reached for the free list until we've touched every object in the heap. Here's a
在我们接触到堆中的每个对象之前，不会到达空闲列表。这是一个
little example. So, we're starting out here with a, a heap and we're gonna assume
举个小例子。所以，我们从一个堆开始，我们要假设
there's just one root for simplicity. And here are all the objects and initially
简约只有一个根基。这里是所有的物体，最初
their marked bits are zero and we do have a free list, an initial free list over
它们的标记位是零，我们确实有一个空闲列表，初始空闲列表
here. Notice that, you know, there's a little bit of memory that is on the free
这里。请注意，您知道，有一点内存是空闲的
list. Okay. So, after the mark phase, what has happened? Well, we've gone through,
列表。好吧。那么，在标记阶段之后，发生了什么？嗯，我们已经谈过了，
and touched all the reachable objects. So, we started with A and, of course, we set
触摸所有可触及的物体。所以，我们从A开始，当然，我们设置了
its mark bit to one. And then we followed pointers reachable from A, set the mark
它的标记位为1。然后我们跟随从A可达的指针，设置标记
bit there. Follow the pointer reachable from C, set the mark bit there. And so we
在那里咬一口。跟随可从C到达的指针，将标记位设置在那里。所以我们
wind up A, C, and E being marked, nothing else is marked, okay. And now the sweep
结束A、C和E的标记，其他的都没有标记，好吗？现在是清扫
phase will go through memory, it's going to reset all the marked bits to zero. And
相位将通过存储器，它将把所有标记的位重置为0。和
as it finds unreachable objects, in this case B and D, it's going to add them to
当它发现无法到达的对象(在本例中是B和D)时，它将把它们添加到
the free list and so what we'll wind up the free list will wind up being a linked
空闲列表以及我们将结束的空闲列表最终将是一个链接的
list of, of, of blocks of memory that are available for future allocations.
可供将来分配的内存块的、的列表。